Guide to the Mabel Dodge Luhan Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1910-1953; Series II; 8.76; (21 boxes)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Evans, John (1902-)
      - "Drowned--Almost," story, printed version, The Morristonian, 1919 (Box 61, Folder 1599)
      - "The Inarticulate Genius," scenario, typescript carbon, 1924 (Box 61, Folder 1600)
      - "The Life of Charlemagne," thesis, holograph, 1921 Jan (Box 61, Folder 1601)
      - [Notebook of poems], holograph, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1602)
      - Poems, holograph, typescript and typescript carbon, 1916-36, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1603)
      - [School "Themes" and notes], holograph and typescript carbon, corrected, 1915-19, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1604-1605)
      - [School "Themes"], typescript, corrected, 1914-22, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1606)
      - Untitled poems, holograph and typescript carbon, 1919-23, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1607)
    - Fadiman, Clifton
      - "The Reviewing Business," article, printed version, Harper's Magazine, [1941?] (Box 62, Folder 1608)
    - Flint, Ralph
      - "Lily Lady Goes West," article, printed version, Town & Country, 1943 Jan (Box 62, Folder 1609)
    - Foote, Mary
      - "Portrait of Mabel Dodge," holograph manuscript, 1912 Sep (Box 62, Folder 1610)
    - Fox, Douglas
      - "Fifty Years of Polo: Mr. Seward Cary's Story..." article, printed version, Polo, 1930 Mar (Box 62, Folder 1611)
    - Fredericks, P. G.
      - "How to Get Rich by Writing," article, printed version, Mademoiselle, 1942 Aug (Box 62, Folder 1612)
    - Friedman, Murray M.
      - "Utilization of Antibody for the Localization..." article, printed version, The American Journal of Roentgenology and Radium Therapy, 1945 Dec (Box 62, Folder 1613)
    - [Geecurley?], John
      - "Callers," poem, typescript, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1614)
    - Giovannitti, Arturo
      - "Evil Wishes for the War Year," poem, printed version, 1916 Jan 7 (Box 62, Folder 1615)
    - Gish, Lillian
      - "The Birth of the Films," film scenario, typescript carbon, 1939 Jul 24 (Box 62, Folder 1616)
    - Gogarty, Oliver St. John
      - "They Think They Know Joyce," article, printed version, Saturday Review, 1950 Mar 18 (Box 62, Folder 1617)
    - Gold, Michael
      - "Mabel Luhan's Slums," article, printed version, New Masses, 1936 Sep 1 (Box 62, Folder 1618)
    - Goldsmith, Reuben
      - "On Human Evolution," poem, typescript carbon, 1946 Sep 17 (Box 62, Folder 1619)
    - Gregory, [Harold?] Anthony
      - Untitled poems, typescript, 1940 (Box 62, Folder 1620)
    - Gulick, Luther Halsey
      - "The Desires of American Girls," article, typescript, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1621)
      - "Team Work in Social Life: An Address to the Girls of America," [presentation?], typescript, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1622)
      - ["That bunch of flowers..."], poem, holograph, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1623)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins
      - "Sex Antagonism," lecture, drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1624)
    - Hausner, Eric P.
      - "Clinical Evaluation of Dicumarinyl Derivatives... " article, printed version, Circulation, 1951 Feb (Box 62, Folder 1625)
    - Haweis, Stephen
      - "The Dispenser of Justice," article, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1626)
        See also: Scrapbooks, "Untitled," Box 98, folder 2267
    - Hicks, Granville
      - "The Legend of John Reed," article, printed version, New Masses, 1937 Oct 19 (Box 62, Folder 1627)
    - Hughes, Langston
      - "A House in Taos," poem, typescript, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1628)
    - [Jeffers, Una?]
      - "The Dog's Grave," poem, holograph, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1629)
    - Johnson, Walter Willard ("Spud")
      - "Adventure," poem, holograph, 1925 (Box 62, Folder 1630)
      - "A Book Full of Poetry," review of Winter in Taos, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1631)
      - "Camposanto," poem, typescript carbon, 1926 (Box 62, Folder 1632)
      - "City Birds," poem, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1633)
      - "Evening Poems," typescript carbon, 1926 (Box 62, Folder 1634)
      - "Hacienda," poem, typescript carbon, 1926 (Box 62, Folder 1635)
      - "Indian Song," poem, holograph, 1921-23 (Box 62, Folder 1636)
        Includes "The Pure of Heart"
      - "Miniature of Mabel," poem, typescript, corrected, 1926 (Box 62, Folder 1637)
      - "Nose-Gay," poem, drafts, typescript carbon, 1924, 1927 (Box 62, Folder 1638)
      - "The Old Maid," poem, typescript, corrected, 1927 (Box 62, Folder 1639)
      - "Old Man Fell In," poem, typescript, 1924 (Box 62, Folder 1640)
      - "Patricio Came," [story?], printed version, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1641)
      - "Poppies," poem, drafts, holograph and typescript, 1921-24 (Box 62, Folder 1642)
      - "A Quiet Book," review of Winter in Taos, drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1643)
      - "Song of Going to Fetch the Water," poem, typescript, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1644)
        Includes "All Summer Long"
      - "To a Young Lady from New York," poem, typescript carbon, 1927 (Box 62, Folder 1645)
      - "Yellow," poem, printed version (2 copies), 1924 Dec
    - Jones, Robert Edmond
      - [Diary], typescript carbon, corrected, 1919 (Box 62, Folder 1646)
      - [Lecture on theater], typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1647)
      - "The Theatre as it has been and as it is," article, typescript, corrected (Box 62, Folder 1648)
    - Justema, William
      - "Portrait," article, printed version, Year Magazine, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1649)
    - Kiker, Henry
      - The Daily Forward, newsletter, typescript carbon, 1940 (Box 62, Folder 1650)
    - Kirschman, ----
      - [Lecture on sexual intercourse and pleasure], typescript carbon, corrected, 1911 (Box 62, Folder 1651)
    - Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert)
      - "The First Lady Chatterley," galley proof, corrected, 1944
      - "A Modern Lover," galley proof, n.d.
      - "New Mexico," article, typescript carbon, corrected, [1931?] (Box 62, Folder 1652)
      - [Notes on Southwest], holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1653)
      - "The Proper Study of Mankind," article, printed version, Vanity Fair, 1924 Jan (Box 62, Folder 1654)
    - Lehman, B. H. (Benjamin Harrison)
      - "The Amenities of Book Selecting," article, printed version, The Library Journal, 1939 Sep 1 (Box 62, Folder 1655)
    - Litvinov, Ivy
      - "Surrender to the Sea," poem, typescript (Box 62, Folder 1656)
    - Loy, Mina
      - "The Beneficent Garland," poem, holograph, 1914 Jan (Box 62, Folder 1657)
      - "Feminist Manifesto," holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1658)
      - "International Psycho-democracy," manifesto, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1659)
      - "Involutions," poem, holograph, 1914 (Box 62, Folder 1660)
      - "The Prototype," holograph manuscript, corrected, 1914 Feb 28 (Box 62, Folder 1661)
    - MacKaye, Percy
      - "Mabel: a [sketch?]," poem, holograph, 1916 Mar 28 (Box 63, Folder 1662)
    - Maloney, Russell
      - "Dancing Hamlet," article, printed version, The New Yorker, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1663)
    - Martinez, Avalina
      - [Personal statement], holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1664)
    - Merz, Max
      - "!," poem, holograph, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1665)
    - Morris, Joe Alex
      - "Taos, New Mexico," article, printed version, The Saturday Evening Post, 1950 Jul 22
    - Mozley, Loren
      - "Table Song," poems, typescript, 1926 (Box 63, Folder 1666)
      - "Taos Poems," poems, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1667)
    - Mumford, Clare Dana
      - "Polaris," poem, typescript carbon, 1943 (Box 63, Folder 1668)
    - Munson, Gorham
      - "Orage in America," article, printed version, Dynamic America, 1940 May (Box 63, Folder 1669)
    - Murphy, Carolyn Cushman
      - "Coyotes," poem, typescript, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1670)
      - "Maltrata," poem, typescript, 1923 Jul (Box 63, Folder 1671)
    - Orliac, Jehanne d'
      - "Le second mari de Lady Chatterley," synopsis, typescript, corrected (Box 63, Folder 1672)
    - Pyle, Mita W.
      - Untitled poem, holograph, 1934 Sep (Box 63, Folder 1673)
    - [Rauh?], Ida
      - "Joyse Juicy Mabled, Mobled," holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1674)
    - Reed, John (1887-1920)
      - "The Colorado Man," essay, typescript, typescript carbon and holograph, corrected, with proofreaders' marks and printer's annotations, [1914?] (Box 63, Folder 1675)
      - "First Draught for I.W.W. Pageant," outline, typescript, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1676)
      - "Florence," poem, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1677)
      - Untitled play, drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 63, Folder 1678)
      - Untitled poems, holograph, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 63, Folder 1679)
    - Robinson, Edwin Arlington
      - "Eros Turannos," poem, printed version, Poetry, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1680)
    - [Rogers, Robert Emmons?]
      - ["Dear Mabel, while you're able..."], poem, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1681)
      - ["I could not know..."], poem, holograph, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1682)
    - Rolo, Charles J.[ames?]
      - "Salons and Saloons of a Century," article, printed version, Town & Country, 1946 Dec (Box 63, Folder 1683)
    - Rompapas, John
      - [ The Book of My Life ?], typescript carbon and holograph, corrected, [ca. 1914] (Box 63, Folder 1684)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul
      - "John Marin's Career," article, printed version, The New Republic, 1937 Apr 14 (Box 63, Folder 1685)
    - Rudhyar, Dane
      - "The Outline of a Lecture Course..." outline, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1686)
      - "Project of Studies in the Evaluation of the Social and Indiviudal..." proposal, typescript (Box 63, Folder 1687)
    - Ruthven, Madeleine
      - "Under Glass," poem, printed version, [1932 Jun 4?] (Box 63, Folder 1688)
      - "The Window Ransom," poem, printed version, 1932 Jun 4 (Box 63, Folder 1689)
    - Sanchez, John B.
      - "Believe it or not," article, printed version, n.d.
    - Scripps, Robert Paine
      - "An Epitaph," poem, printed version, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1690)
    - Sergeant, Elizabeth Shepley
      - "Sphinx of Taos Desert," article, printed version, Satuday Review (2 copies), 1938 Nov 26 (Box 63, Folder 1691)
    - Slaughter, Stella
      - "The Story of Ruth," holograph manuscript, 1940-41 (Box 63, Folder 1692)
    - Soracle, S.
      - "Why Mabel Dodge is not a Good Writer," review, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1693)
    - Spiel, Hilde
      - "Three Wise Ladies of Taos," article, printed version, The New Statesman and Nation (2 copies), 1952 Aug 16 (Box 63, Folder 1694)
    - Spingarn, Joel Elias
      - "Harry Thurston Peck," poem, galley, International, [1914?] (Box 63, Folder 1695)
    - Sprague, [Alice?]
      - "Case Study," research notes, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1696)
    - Starobin, Joseph
      - "The Heart of Foreign Policy," review, printed version, [ New Masses ?], 1943 Jun 29 (Box 63, Folder 1697)
    - Stein, Gertrude
      "Portrait of Mabel Dodge at the Villa Curonia"
      See: Writings, Articles and Essays, "Speculations," printed version, Camera Work, Box 44, folder 1362
    - Stein, Leo (1872-1947)
      - ["The conception of a mechanically complete universe..."] notebook, holograph, and transcription, typescript, annotated by MDL, 1910-11 (Box 63, Folder 1698)
      - ["Life we could live for the joy of living..."], holograph fragment, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1699)
      - [On Art], typescript carbon, corrected, 1923 (Box 63, Folder 1700)
      - [On Saints], typescript carbon, corrected, 1923 (Box 63, Folder 1701)
      - "World War," poem, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1702)
      - Untitled poems, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 63, Folder 1703)
    - Sterne, Maurice
      - ["Art is what is put in..."], aphorism, holograph, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1704)
    - Strickland, Dwight
      - "Wind do Something to these Waters," poem, holograph (Box 63, Folder 1705)
        Includes note by MDL
    - Swaine, Ruth
      - "At River House," poem, typescript, 1953 Sep (Box 63, Folder 1706)
      - "Millicent Rogers' Indian Heaven," article, printed version, Saturday Home Magazine (Box 63, Folder 1707)
    - Thomas, Grace Billheimer
      - ["On the Banks of the Jemez..."], poems, holograph, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1708)
      - "The Swan Song of the Trees," poem, holograph, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1709)
    - Tucker, Blanche C.
      - "My Eyes," poem, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1710)
    - Valentine, James
      - "Sonnet XVII," poem, typescript, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1711)
    - Vorse, Mary Heaton
      - "I've Come to Stay," [story?], printed version, Metropolitan, fragment, 1917 Oct (Box 63, Folder 1712)
      - "Winter," story, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1713)
    - Wallace, Henry A.[gard?]
      - "An Open Letter to Premier Stalin," article, printed version, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1714)
    - Wallace, Lew [Barrington?]
      - "Death Comes to the Rolling Stone," [story?], typescript, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1715)
    - Waters, Frank
    - [Weber, Max?]
      - ["There was one living..."] story, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1716)
      - Untitled manuscript, typescript, 1914 (Box 63, Folder 1717)
    - Wilder, Thornton
      - "Taos," holograph manuscript, 1934 (Box 63, Folder 1718)
        Includes drawings on verso
    - Williams, Charles
      - "Sensuality and Substance," article, printed version, [ Theology ], [1939] (Box 63, Folder 1719)
    - Young, Stark
      - "Robert Edmond Jones," article, printed version, The New Republic (Box 63, Folder 1720)
    - ----, Andra
      - "Now it is Autumn and the Falling Fruit..." article, printed version, Kaleidoscope, 1938 Sep 30 (Box 63, Folder 1721)
    - Unidentified
      - "Dorothy Brett Writes About Coronation of Edward VII," review, printed version, El Crepusculo, 1953 Jun 4 (Box 63, Folder 1722)
      - "The Monumental Simplicity in the Pictorial Art of Maurice Sterne," article, printed version, Current Opinion, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1723)
      - Poems and sketches, 1933-36, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1724)
      - "The Talk of the Town," article, printed version, The New Yorker, 1940 Feb 3 (Box 63, Folder 1725)
      - "The World, the Flesh, and the Devil," article, printed version, Newsletter and Wasp, 1939 May 19 (Box 63, Folder 1726)
- Photographs, 1859-1951; Series III; 7.3; (18 boxes)
  Series III, Photographs, is organized into twelve subseries.
  - MABEL DODGE LUHAN
    - Mabel Dodge Luhan Alone
      - Portraits, [ca. 1890-1900] (Box 64, Folder 1727)
      - Portraits, [ca 1900-10] (Box 64, Folder 1728)
      - In Provincetown, 1914 (Box 64, Folder 1729)
      - At Finney Farm, Croton-on-Hudson, [ca. 1915] (Box 64, Folder 1730)
      - Portraits, [ca. 1915] (Box 64, Folder 1731)
      - Wearing serape, [ca. 1917] (Box 64, Folder 1732)
      - With kettle, 1920 (Box 64, Folder 1733)
      - Wearing hat, 1931 (Box 64, Folder 1734)
      - Wearing serape, [1931?] (Box 64, Folder 1735)
      - On horse, 1938 (Box 64, Folder 1736)
      - Standing near car, 1946 Jan 23 (Box 64, Folder 1737)
      - Sitting with book and dog, 1947 Aug 15 (Box 64, Folder 1738)
        Photograph by "Dr. Brill"
      - Portraits, [ca. 1920-] (Box 64, Folder 1739-1747)
      - Portraits, [ca. 1920-] (Box 64, Folder 1748)
    - Mabel Dodge Luhan with Others
      - Brett, Dorothy, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1749)
        Photograph by Cady Wells
      - Brinig, Myron, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1750)
      - Dasburg, Andrew (Box 65, Folder 1751)
      - Dodge, Edwin Sherrill and John Evans, [1905?] (Box 65, Folder 1752)
      - Evans, John, [ca. 1902-30] (Box 65, Folder 1753)
        With "Mary," Clarence Thompson and unidentified man and woman
      - Evans, Karl and John Evans, [1902?] (Box 65, Folder 1754)
        Studio portrait by Hall
      - Evans, [Nancy?] and [Natalie?] (Box 65, Folder 1755)
      - Foote, Mary and Tony Luhan, 1921, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1756)
      - Gillmore, Inez Haynes, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1757)
      - Given, Thelma, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1758)
      - Hapgood, Miriam, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1759)
      - Jeffers, Robinson, 1934-37, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1760)
        With "Adrian," Frieda Lawrence and unidentified woman
      - Johnson, Walter Willard ("Spud"), n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1761)
      - Lawrence, Frieda von Richthofen, [1938?], n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1762)
        With Dorothy Brett
      - [Levien?], Sonya, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1763)
      - Luhan, Tony, 1946-49, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1764-1765)
        With Dorothy Brett and unidentified others
      - MacKaye, Percy, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1766)
        With Tony Luhan
      - Meyers, Ralph, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1767)
      - Montague, Sara Cook Ganson (mother), n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1768)
        With unidentified man
      - Native American Indians (Box 65, Folder 1769-1770)
      - Rauh, Ida, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1771)
        With Ralph Meyers
      - Rogers, "Bobby" and John Evans, 1914 (Box 65, Folder 1772)
      - Sprague, Alice, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1773)
      - Sterne, Maurice, [1917?] (Box 65, Folder 1774)
      - Thompson, Clarence, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1775)
      - Van Vechten, Carl, 1934 Apr 12 (Box 65, Folder 1776)
        Photographs by Van Vechten
      - Weaver, Elizabeth, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1777)
      - Wells, Cady, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1778)
      - Wilder, Thornton, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1779)
        Photograph by K.W. Herrmann
      - Young-Hunter, John, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1780)
        With Bob Scripps and unidentified woman
      - Groups of people, [ca. 1905-50] (Box 65, Folder 1781-1783)
        With John Archuleto, Witter Bynner, John C[ollier?], Dasburg, Jo Davidson, Foote, Gillmore, Alice and "Millie" Henderson, "Jimmy" Hopper, Una and Robinson Jeffers, Spud Johnson, Frieda Lawrence, Sinclair Lewis, Tony Luhan, Meyers, Alfonso Ossorio, Dorothy Parker, Angelino Ravagli, Lincoln Steffens, Maurice Sterne, Edward Weston, Ella Young, Young-Hunter and others
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1784-1786)
  - STUDIO AND ARTISTS' PORTRAITS OF MABEL DODGE LUHAN
    - Abbe, [James Edward?], n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1787)
    - Associated Press, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1788)
    - Blanche, Jacques-Emile, [ca. 1910] (Box 66, Folder 1789)
      With John Evans
    - [Bravo, M.?], n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1790)
    - Connell, Will, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1791)
    - Evans, ----, [1880s] (Box 66, Folder 1792)
    - Goldberg, ----, 1912 (Box 66, Folder 1793)
    - Hagemeyer, Johan, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1794)
    - Hall, ----, [1890s] (Box 66, Folder 1795)
    - [Käsebier, Gertrude?], n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1796)
    - [Lynes, Russell?], n.d.
    - Numa Blanc fils, [ca. 1904] (Box 66, Folder 1797)
    - Rockwood, ----, [1880s] (Box 66, Folder 1798)
    - Sylls, Alan, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1799)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1933-34 (Box 66, Folder 1800-1803)
    - Wells, Cady, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1804)
    - Weston, Edward, 1933 (Box 66, Folder 1805)
    - Unidentified, [ca. 1880-1900] (Box 66, Folder 1806)
  - MABEL DODGE LUHAN IN ARTWORK
    - Jacques-Emile Blanche paintings, [ca. 1910] (Box 66, Folder 1807)
    - Florence Bradley painting, 1910 (Box 66, Folder 1808)
    - Witter Bynner sketch, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1809)
    - Jo Davidson sculpture, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1810)
    - Mary Foote painting, fragment, 1912 (Box 66, Folder 1811)
    - John Young-Hunter painting, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1812)
  - TONY LUHAN
    - Tony Luhan Alone
      - Portraits, [ca. 1920-50] (Box 67, Folder 1813-1814)
        Includes photographs by Ansel Adams, Sally Flavin and [Edward Weston?]
      - Snapshots, 1929-46, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1815-1823)
        Includes photograph by Dr. Brill
    - Tony Luhan with Others
      - [Angulo?], Jaime de, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1824)
      - Archuleto, John, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1825)
      - Brett, Dorothy, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1826)
      - Evans, John, 1918, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1827)
        With unidentified men
      - Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert), n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1828)
      - Lawrence, Frieda von Richthofen and unidentified woman (Box 67, Folder 1829)
      - Mauldin, Natalie and child, 1949 May (Box 67, Folder 1830)
      - Meyers, Ralph, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1831)
        With unidentified others
      - Montgomery, Mary Binney, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1832)
      - Parsons, Elsie [Worthington Clews?] and "Raeh" (Box 67, Folder 1833)
      - Rauh, Ida, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1834)
      - Robinson, Leighton, 1927 Nov (Box 67, Folder 1835)
      - Sichez, Jan, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1836)
      - Sterne, Maurice and "Pedro", [1917?] (Box 67, Folder 1837)
      - Stokowska, Evangeline and children, [1930s?] (Box 67, Folder 1838)
      - Thompson, Clarence, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1839)
      - Van Vechten, Carl, [ca. 1933-34?] (Box 67, Folder 1840)
        With Witter Bynner
      - Young, Ella, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1841)
      - ----, Alfred, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1842)
      - ----, Emily, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1843)
      - ----, Evelyn, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1844)
      - ----, Madeline, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1845)
      - ----, Shim and unidentified child (Box 67, Folder 1846)
      - Groups of people, 1932-38, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1847-1848)
        With Mary Foote, D. H. Lawrence and others
        Includes photographs by Miguel Flores and Foto Mendoza
      - Unidentified, 1937-49, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1849-1852)
  - FAMILY
    - Belden, ----, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1853)
      Studio portrait by Upson
    - Cook, Marianna, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1854)
    - Cook, "Grandma" (Box 68, Folder 1855)
      Studio portraits by Numan Blanc fils and G. C. Cox
    - Evans, Alice Henderson, [1920s], n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1856-1857)
      Includes portraits by Edward Steichen and Marceau
    - Evans, Bonnie, [1930-40s] (Box 68, Folder 1858)
      With unidentified women
    - Evans, Claire Spencer, [ca. 1930s] (Box 68, Folder 1859)
      Includes portrait by Edward Weston
    - Evans, John, 1902-[ca. 50] (Box 69, Folder 1860-1868)
      With Edwin Sherrill Dodge, Nelly Fries, Marry Hamlin, Ray Otis, Concha Eliseo and others
      Includes studio portraits by Hall, G. Brogi, and Beach
    - Evans, John, 1902-[ca. 50] (Box 69, Folder 1869-1870)
    - Evans, John and family, [ca. 1912]-46 (Box 69, Folder 1871)
      Includes studio portraits by Juanita Ball
    - Evans, John Ganson (great uncle), n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1872)
    - Evans, Karl and John Evans, 1902 (Box 69, Folder 1873)
    - Evans, Letitue, [1920-30s] (Box 69, Folder 1874)
    - Evans, Nancy, [1920-30s] (Box 69, Folder 1875)
    - Evans, Natalie, [1920-30s] (Box 69, Folder 1876-1877)
      Includes studio portraits by Bachrach and unidentified woman
      See also: Evans, Alice Henderson, Box 68, folders 1856-1857
    - Evans, Sandy, [1930-40s] (Box 69, Folder 1878-1879)
      With Bonnie Evans and Patricia Smith
    - Evans girls, [1930-40s] (Box 70, Folder 1880-1883)
    - Evans, ----, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1884)
    - Field, ----, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1885)
    - Ganson, Charles Frederick, 1859-96, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1886-1887)
      Includes studio portraits by Mora, Ludovici's, Simson and Hall
    - Ganson, "Grandma" (Box 70, Folder 1888)
      Studio portraits by Upson, Simson and Beach
    - Ganson, "Grandpa" (Box 70, Folder 1889)
      Includes studio portraits by Upson and Simson
    - Heredria, Carlos de, n.d.
      Photograph by Kurtz
    - Heredia, Georgia Cook de, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1890)
    - Montague, Sara Cook Ganson, 1878-1905, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1891)
      Includes studio portraits by Bradley & Rulofson, Ludovici's and Degranges
    - O'Malley, Ernie, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1892)
    - Rathbone, Virginia Bacon, [1901?] (Box 70, Folder 1893)
      Studio portrait by Frank